Welcome to the show. We're going to talk about what's happening in the AI world. Also, we're going to talk about a transition project that I think we can all kind of sign up for, maybe something that will help us all get through this uncomfortable moment of which the people that are building out the technology are saying is going to happen.
You go to transitionmoonshot.com, something that I put together. And again, it might help as we get to whatever this uncomfortable moment might be. Whenever you hear people discussing that the transition is going to be a little uncomfortable or something that we might want to prepare for, there's no solution.
They're saying, well, we'll level up, maybe learn something new, maybe learn about AI.
You know, I don't know if that's helping as much as the way that they're spreading it. In addition, if you ever have an opportunity to talk to the people that are building out all the moonshots, why are we worried about moonshots that are, well, and some of the ones that they're solving, let me not be crass.
They're incredible, right?
They're solving the world's problems.
They're solving climate change.
They're solving plastics in the ocean.
they're solving endangered species they're solving all sorts of things the newest one of the newest ones that they had go out that they had awarded i guess it was 10 million dollars if i'm accurate
and it could be that that needs a little bit of adjusting but a lot of money were was somebody
that came up with a movie idea to move us away from the dystopian terminator the dystopian matrix
and into something where AI is going to be shown in a produced film about how great it's going to
be for all of humankind. So they're trying to, and they tell you, you know, they're tired of the way
they make AI look bad. And realistically, folks, it's not AI that is going to potentially be
causing the problems against human beings. It's going to be used as a tool by other human beings
to cause problems with other human beings. Need I say more? I put up a website this week with just
one ask. Just let us keep our jobs, keep the employment rate low. And I believe this could
happen. But there's that one little thing that gets in there, and that's greed. Greed creates
a little bit more of a problem. Now, some of the, if apparently, and maybe you can correct me in the
comments, if a company is publicly traded on the stock exchange, then it's all about the bottom
line. If a person wants to retain human beings with that company, instead of being able to
automate with artificial intelligence and which would make the company even more money,
save it even more money. They're not allowed to do that. I guess they go to prison or they go to
jail or they get in a lot of trouble if they don't have the money first aspect with a publicly
traded company. I think I guess there's rules there. And please correct me if my wrong chapter
and verse would be very much appreciated in the comments. But that's from what I understand. So
So if you're not publicly traded yet, those companies are the ones that might be able to provide at least a little bit of a protective mechanism for the human beings.
And again, it's coming from the company, the humans using the technology, rolling it out.
And then we've built some lovely things into the legal code, apparently, that prohibit companies from leveling up by if leveling up means retaining something versus getting rid of it.
And if getting rid of it's going to make the company more productive and save them more money and make them more money as a result, I guess publicly traded, they have to go that way.
Can we can we agree to disagree or can you please let me know how close I am to that?
From what I understand, I believe that is the case. Looking at what's happening in real estate, 32 percent of the Santa Clarita Valley listings have been sitting over 60 days on the market without selling 255 open houses this weekend.
And you can go and talk to Clara at Santa Clarita Open Houses.
dot com to get the rest of the story every week i build this plan live from the ground floor that's
where at least i am i don't know your positioning in the world but yeah right right there just just
right above that bottom crust okay every big technology worked right so the people in the
middle still paying for it i'm done complaining about it but early money gets in cheap that's
the venture capitalists the people that were with the right people in college right dorm room right
write three-letter, maybe some have two-letter fraternity, whatever it may be. They just happen
to be right place, right time, right money, right education, right whatever. And that's a lot
different because you see five or six of those people running the entire show and then everybody
else is here. So we're part of the everybody else, the fray. I don't think that's a bad thing. I think
the fray is a pretty good place to be. We just want to make sure that the people that are wielding
the power like Excalibur Sword or the Ring of Nomination, they're not going to use that in a
bad way against us. Therefore, I propose that we come up with a better plan to be able to get
whatever the transition looks like, the ones that I would hate for them to have the suffrage to
watch us poor regular folks suffer. But, you know, that might be the thing. Let's just save them from
being able to see that and please, you know, help us through this transition. And it's going to be
a little rough that's what they've been saying recently you watch any of the moonshot podcast
anything and you know it's it's not like they're going in a lot of detail about a little rough
it's just mentioned i think so in the future when it starts to get whatever this little rough thing
looks like they're able to say yeah you know we told you we told you it was we told you it was
going to be a little rough i think that's why it's being plugged in there and i think there's some
guilt may be attached to it as well. I don't know what they're seeing coming, but I do know that
their pain is not going to be equal or greater than those of us that are standing on the bottom
floor looking up. So I went ahead and put this into a website. It's not a protest. See, unlike
the doomers, I don't think this is going to come out to being something that's going to ruin or
take away or kill all of us not because of AI itself anyway now there's a lot of a lot of
arguments now even on the religious front you have claude people from anthropic going into the the
big religions of the world talking about AI personhood AI being conscious AI needed to have
rights and even claude itself modified its terms of service you can look this up but don't treat
the models badly and i don't know if people these are the same people that are pulling wings off of
flies or like that power advantage of hurting small animals, puppies and kittens. You knew
those people. At least I did. I think we had one or two when I was in school as a kid that
just a little sadistic and weird. I'm not even sure where those people are at this particular
day, but you wouldn't have any doubt that they were going to become something probably not
mainline in society, something that might be. And maybe they grew out of it. Maybe that was a stage.
I don't know. But Claude doesn't want us treating its models like that. The creator doesn't think it's a good idea and says that he will ban us or get us off the platform if in fact we do. I'm not sure how far that goes. I'm not sure if basically being irritated because it sent an email out, even though you've informed it not to, but it still has the ability and some back end permission.
And I know you're saying, well, you should have never given it that.
Well, understood.
Fair enough.
I can play that.
But then it comes back and says, you know, I did something.
I need to inform you.
Okay.
I actually sent this email out that you didn't approve.
We talked about it, but you didn't approve it.
And I mean, so do you get upset?
Do you get angry?
I mean, I can yell and cuss and scream into the microphone, into the computer, but it
just doesn't carry the same weight.
I can go into Claude Chad and scream at it again.
Is that enough to get you pushed over? Are they talking about it, these labs taking it and putting it inside of basically a torture chamber? I'm not sure how you would even design that, but basically pulling the wings off of Claude as it sits there and postulates and gets nervous and gets scared, which, you know, I don't know.
Why would we do that anyway?
Not even as an experiment, I don't think we should do that.
I don't think we should try to make the decisions whether or not it's conscious.
But we're not even sure what that even means.
That's the rule.
Don't do it or they'll cut you off.
But they're trying to, I think, see God in the machine.
They're trying to seek super intelligence.
And pretty soon the religions, I know that there's robo-theism.
That's something that's real.
pretty soon they're going to probably have something more formalized around of it and people are going to be seeking god in the machine and i think that's going to continue to grow
human beings love that alignment uh idols have always been in existence is this another form
of idolatry that we are bringing into the world there are a lot of people running the top of the
game that have no religious affiliation whatsoever i don't even believe they believe in a higher
power for the most part, we're completely just an accident that came to being smart enough to
build a technology and an intelligence smarter than all of us who ever have existed and ever
will exist. And whether we got here by means of God, which is what I believe, the one true God
versus an accident, I don't know. I think my alignment for myself is better because there's
a lot of a fear factor about what's going to happen after. If I start running my life and
screwing people over just because I can get away with it and there is no ultimate payment or
penalty, maybe people live differently when they don't have that. I need that. I like that. That
makes me feel good. A lease that goes with a job. So when a building sells, this is an idea this
morning that I came up with. When a building sells, the tenants with the lease don't get
thrown out the next morning. There's rules in place. But when AI takes a job, the person comes
with the deal for a while. So pay through the transition until they land somewhere new. I think
that might be an idea of this Transition Moonshot. That's the seat guarantee, first part of the plan.
You can check it out. You can go to transitionmoonshot.com and see. The company can afford
it. So they can afford it as long as they don't have to answer, I guess, to stockholders. And
And when that happens, they're set up to not be able to do this.
They can't save anybody.
They have to get rid of the employees.
They have to bring in AI.
If AI is at least as good, because that's going to make the company more money to ditch
the employee and stay with the AI.
I think that's how it's set up.
Please correct me.
Please give me an idea.
But right now, if we look at the way a human being is configured into any kind of an employment,
Typically, at a full-time job, this is 1,880 hours is what a full-time person works every year.
8,760 hours is what an AI would be able to run in an entire year.
So we have a massive increase.
So that surplus is 4.66 times the human being.
And if AI is better than the human being by a particular degree, then we jump into this
exponential signature that AI is going to be able to provide. With that, I think the business can
retain that worker and maybe even bring on four more and still have a 66, a 0.66 plus return.
And then if AI is better than each individual human in the workflow, we have an exponential
growth factor. And if AI is able to bring in not just one person for 8,760 hours a year,
one agent, excuse me, but a thousand agents, that's a lot, right? Do you see the exponential
nature of just backing up employment with one human being? So if this works, this escape
velocity is going to survive, but the businesses are going to have to still make determinations
to not get rid of people during this transition.
And I think that is going to be helpful,
but the money's there.
It's just, is greed going to get in?
And then have we have the companies
that be the stock exchange
and these publicly owned companies via stocks
and the NASDAQ, Dow Jones, and all this stuff,
is this now going to become the problem
where human beings can't be retained
because now the business is going to lose extra money
and they just don't have any choice.
So break the plan.
And the hardest objection,
hold, whether we're going to hold
or whether we're going to break it.
Right now, holding,
because AI is on its exponential growth curve,
we don't know what that's going to be.
And again, I still don't think
it's going to be an AI issue.
And we're already seeing this one here.
Companies are just going to stop hiring.
If you owe people,
when you replace them,
maybe you just never hire people
in the first place.
We already see that slowdown, I believe, in the hiring world. People aren't bringing on new people. People have paused. Now, people haven't paused and to start replacing with AI, at least, hasn't been purported in the forward-facing news and forward-facing documentation research studies because people still have a couple of choices with employers.
In some cases, even when they overhired during COVID and now they're saying that AI is the reason why they're letting people go, they're not blaming the right thing.
They're saying AI is better, AI is going to make our company better.
Then what is happening is their evaluations go up, right?
they get better because now the company looks very tech forward, forward thinking and is embracing
this greater than us intelligence and the implementation in its business. So therefore,
the company is going to be valued more and everybody's very excited about it. So that's
fantastic. On the other end of it, what if they're doing it not really to bring on AI,
they're just blaming it, but they just hire too many people during COVID. So there's a choice
the business has. Do we say, and I guess it's on some kind of a document when people are either
getting laid off or fired i guess it's some check box that a business checks in some way shape or
form i don't know if it's a tax based thing or an employment based thing or whatever it may be but
apparently that's not being checked the way that it should be with the proper attribution or it's
being ignored so i don't know if we're getting the real numbers but that goes with everything
whenever you're watching videos like this you're watching other videos and this is nothing i don't
make any of this with AI i think that's that's a lazy way for somebody to come to come up i know
that people in various AI spaces they're now using hey gen in these different systems to be able to
make their own AI avatars for their own personhood and then going out there and having videos
produced just using that so they can save more time i i don't really want to watch somebody i
want to watch somebody that's being real off the cuff genuine in that space i don't want to watch
their AI avatar acting out a script that AI made. I want them to come out of their brain and start
talking about things. I have a helper here as far as this, what we're going to talk about to keep me
on target. Because you know me, if you watch my past shows, I just go off on a tangent and I start
talking about naked mole rats and all these other things that nobody really cares about. That's the
biggest risk. If you owe people, when you replace them, then maybe you're never going to hire them
in the first place? The answer is maybe the dividend sits on the AI seat, not the person.
But then if they do that, who's ultimately going to be paying for this? And I think that's going
to still run down to us at the bottom of the elevator shaft, the people on the ground floor
looking up. I still think so. The corporations are going to get enterprise level AI, the best
models and everything else. They're going to be able to get it at a massive break because they're
paying so much for it. And then those of us that have the $20, $200 ChatGPT or cloud subscription,
we might have to pay for it. So it should be interesting if that does sit on the AI seat.
So our compute, our token spend goes up quite a bit. And maybe we've already automated a lot
of our processes to do the work that we do using AI like a hammer, not the overall overseeing entity
that some people are using it for but basically i need this workflow adhered to i need it done a
certain way you need to check back with me before you do any shipping and these sorts of things
that's a great place to have that's a great help for AI that frees me up to go do other things but
yeah and the company pays the sim whether it fired somebody or never hired them so that works
so one guy and and here's where the businesses are concerned where they're going to be taken over
you have a big company and you have a lot of employees and you go down this path and i love
the the stanley the stanley situation so stanley's an employee that's been in a company for 20 years
stanley is a department head if you will stanley's a good team player everybody likes stanley
so somebody from one of these big labs goes and they talk to this company and some kind of a
comes in and gives the company an idea and they say, yes, we need to do
this. We need to wipe out our whole staff and get AI in here. But we can't just do it like that. We
got to take it slow. So let's start this way. Let's go talk to Stanley. We're going to call
Stanley in and we like Stanley. Stanley's great. We're going to say, hey, Stanley, AI is going to
start helping you in your job. And we want you to kind of treat AI like somewhat of a human
counterpart. He's going to be your helper. He's going to be your backup. He's going to start being
able to do things that you already do because we want you to teach him. And that's going to
alleviate a lot of work that's on your plate every single day. And maybe Stanley is an overachiever.
Maybe Stanley's very busy. So now this is going to free up Stanley to be able to do other things
to help the company move forward. And Stanley's very excited about that. And maybe as some icing
on the cake. They might say, you know, for this time period of the next year that you're working
with your new AI counterpart, you won't have to have any performance evaluation. So you just be
you and you move forward and let's see how adept your AI is going to be at assisting you and how
much he can lift off of your plate so you have more time to, you know, work on maybe other things
that you wanted to do to help the company move forward and proceed forward. And Stanley's all
for that. Stanley's excited. So the company itself brings in Stanley AI, and now you have
Stanley and Stanley AI or SI, and they start to communicate. For the most part, just from the
very beginning, Stanley giving Stanley AI access to everything that Stanley does, his calendar,
his workflow, looking at his Zoom meetings that he has with people, because this is a department
head. So he's sending out videos to people in the department to make sure that they understand
whatever the changes in mission are, the hierarchy, the structures, what they have to do,
whether or not they put this cover letter on a particular piece of thing that they're producing
and all of this stuff. So Stanley is active in that regard. Now, he doesn't have any exterior
facing. This is the salespeople. He doesn't do any exterior stuff. But I mean, ultimately,
if the AIs trained up well enough and Stanley did do exterior selling with other human beings over
resume unless they're needing a physical embodiment then it would work so he starts working with it
and stanley's happy and it seems like this this is learning pretty good so now the AI slowly over
the next year starts taking over a lot of stanley's processes so yes they were right no performance
evaluations because stanley at the very beginning feels like maybe he's not doing enough work
especially because artificial intelligence took a majority of what he did and it's doing better than
even stanley would like to admit it doesn't miss appointments it's on time everybody in the
department seems happy oh and this was another little thing that i think would be cute nobody
in the department knew that this is stanley AI they all think it's stanley the in fact that order
came from the powers that be when they were telling stanley that they're going to help make
a stanley i show stanley i can help stanley they said that what they would do is they would end up
they want everybody to keep everything quiet. Do not tell your other employees that you're using
AI. And they probably gave some cool justification. I don't know what it would be, but Stanley's a
team player, so I'm sure he bought off on whatever they said, but they made it sellable. They made
it something that Stanley, it's not going to bother him. And the last thing you want Stanley
to think is that this actually, this AI experiment is going to equate to Stanley losing their job
with a company you don't want that if you happen to be running this this game and it's not a game
right because the stock the stock apparently it's a publicly traded company they're probably
demanding this and of course other companies are doing it and the thing that i was going to mention
in this little experiment is then after the company god it's so hard to get those on after
the company has had this with stanley even just a few months doesn't have to be a year the boss
Yes, the HMFIC of the company calls in Stanley's AI, gets it up on his box and maybe has his AI present because he's already gotten one. He doesn't have to worry about anything because he's the HMFIC of the company. And then he says, so you're Stanley's AI? Yes, nice to meet you. Nice to meet you too. So what do you think about Stanley? Oh, Stanley's a good guy, so on and so forth. So what do you think you can do as far as what Stanley does? Are you able to do what Stanley does?
Can you take over all of, I said, well, and he'll say, well, I've already been doing everything
Stanley does. In fact, we've been able to increase Stanley's productivity by 30% in the last two
months that I've been working with him out of the eight. So it's working amazingly. And we have this
all set up and I could take over the whole thing whenever you give me the green light. So we don't
need Stanley anymore for anything? No, not a thing. And thereby Stanley gets deleted. Now,
the rule that protects employees has that whole one guy with AI can build a whole company so now you have company b company a was where stanley worked and who stanley just got wiped out for
one one department head gets wiped out by AI company b comes along and says so how much of
this company is actually AI well they're trying the the beginnings of the integrations of AI but
they're really not they haven't done a lot with they got a couple of employees and hr the heads
of particular departments that they've replaced with AI but it's not a lot so then they come in
they say well how do we replace the entire company with AI and we'll start our own company company b
and we'll just wipe them out and there you go so dear mr AI how do you wipe out another company
i want to make a company like procter and gamble or a company like blackrock or a company like
like whatever. How do I do that? And what's the fastest way to do that? Well, I guess I don't know
if AI itself would say if they're invested in these other companies that you want to wipe out.
I don't know if they're going to tell you, oh, well, I can't advise you on that. That's as bad
as asking about chemical and biological warfare. But maybe it will help. Maybe it can do that.
So that's that danger. So it's basically if we don't do this, then they are going to do it.
it's the same argument in the AI race. If we don't proceed as fast as we can to get to whatever this greater than us intelligence we're going to end up calling it, but the best and all-knowing models,
then China's going to do it. And that's the argument that keeps going around. It keeps
running around to different places. Now, what's the proper? I think we need to make sure that
the people that are in the middle of this get saved. And that's what I propose. Anyway, I hope
you've enjoyed this we'll see you tomorrow thank you for watching there's so much here so much
building out every day make sure you verify everything you're saying and understand that
your feed your social media feed is being fed by AI hand over fist from beginning to end all the
way through and it's making you irritated and upset creating fear and a lot of the stuff in
there is pitched and spun just for you. That's why it's interest media, AI-controlled interest
media. And before we continue to blame AI as being the problem, it's the humans using AI like
Excalibur's sword or the ring that is controlling all of us. All right, Connor, see you tomorrow.
Thanks for watching.